Alexander Meikopoulos

Front-end software engineer and Project leader with experience on Quality excellence.

With a solid 7-year background in Quality Assurance, I've also co-founded MtopSwap and lead its Engineering & Development. My current expertise is in front-end development, and I'm on the path to becoming a full-stack developer. The rigorous QA practices from my manufacturing experience translate into a detail-oriented approach in tech, aiming for the highest quality in software.



alexander@meikopoulos.com (+30) 6955 255 060 github.com/0xAlexander meikopoulos.com

Experience

Co-founder, Head of Engineering & Development · MtopSwap Feb 2022 - Present

- Co-Founded MtopSwap and lead as Head of Engineering & Strategic Development, driving the project's technical execution and strategic vision.
- Lead the design, development and launch of MtopSwap V2.
- Ensured alignment between strategic objectives and operational execution through close collaboration with the CEO and Lead Developer.
- Contributed hands-on in front-end development, designing and coding key components, while maintaining a focus on guiding the project's technical direction.
- Streamlined operations to keep the platform at the forefront of the industry's rapid evolution
- · Led innovation efforts, prioritized security, and delivered advanced features.

Head of Quality Assurance · Lykomitros Steel Aug 2019 - Present Quality Assurance Engineer Jan 2017 - Aug 2019 QA/QC Administrative Support Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

- Lead the QA department, focusing on renewable energy components in steel manufacturing.
- Maintained industry and client standards, ensuring product integrity for renewable energy.
- Developed procedures, supporting 15+ QC experts and influencing 300+ factory staff
- Authored quality reports, facilitating continuous improvement initiatives.
- Managed 30+ client audits according to ISO 9001, ISO 45001, and ISO 14001, enhancing problem-solving and communication in renewable energy projects.
- Enhanced production processes for consistent quality in renewable energy component manufacturing.
- Created key QA documentation and implemented ISO 45001 and ISO 14001 processes for compliance.
- Executed inspections and audits, leading to corrective actions in manufacturing.
- Provided administrative support for QA/QC, ensuring data management and ISO 9001 conformance.
- Organized quality documentation, supporting audits, and reviews in steel manufacturing.

Digital Systems Administrator - Internship · OTE Group (HTO) Nov 2013 - May 2014

 Gained valuable experience in digital systems administration, focusing on the management of contractors and capital.

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Next.js, React Native, Tailwind CSS

Tools & Platforms

Git, GitHub, Vercel, WordPress, Figma

Additional / Other:

Decentralized Applications (DApps), Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery (CI/CD), ISO Compliance

Selected Projects

MtopSwap - MetaDEX Aggregator

MtopSwap is a next-gen
Decentralized Exchange, that uses
meta-DEX aggregation. I designed it
in Figma and coded it in VS Code with
the Lead Engineer. It's built on
Next.js, MUI, and Tailwind CSS stack,
with the front-end deployed on Vercel
and Nest.js-powered backend on
Railway.

meikopoulos.com

Personal website coded in Visual Studio Code. Built with Next.js and Tailwind CSS, deployed on Vercel.

Education

Thessaliko IEK - Institute of Vocational Training

Diploma (Post-Secondary EQF 5 level) in IT Systems and Applications

Interests

Hiking, Travel, Scl-Fi, Cryptography, Decentralization, Reading